A Guide to the Disaster Files of the Virginia Department of Emergency Management, 1969-2012
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Disaster Files of the Virginia Department of Emergency Management, 1969-2012
The Library of Virginia
53599
23 cu. ft. (23 boxes)
Virginia. Dept. of Emergency Management
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 53599 transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Emergency Management, 25 Apr 22.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the 1950s and 1960s, Virginia's civil defense plan was geared toward the protection of civilian lives in the event of war and restoration of communities and industrial facilities in the event of thermonuclear war. The Emergency Services and Disaster Act of 1973 shifted the agency's focus away from nuclear disaster and toward other types of natural and man-made disasters. It repealed the 1952 act and replaced the Office of Civil Defense with the Office of Emergency Services, led by a State Coordinator of Civil Defense appointed by the Governor. The purpose of the new Office was to "insure that preparations of the State and its political subdivisions will be adequate to deal with...emergencies, and generally to provide for the common defense and to protect the public peace, health and safety, and to preserve the lives and property and economic well-being of the people of the State." Some of the duties of the State Coordinator are: prepare and maintain a State Emergency Operations Plan relating to man-made and natural disasters; coordinate and administer preparedness programs with Federal, State and local government agencies;and provide guidance and assistance to local governments in designing local emergency programs and plans. During a declared emergency operational control of this agency reverts to the Governor.
The Dept. of Emergency Management has undergone several name changes since 1973. In 1974 the agency's name was changed to State Office of Emergency Services. On 14 March 1978, Governor John N. Dalton issued an executive order assigning the functions of the State Energy Office to the State Office of Emergency Services. The agency was renamed the State Office of Emergency and Energy Services. The name was changed to Department of Emergency Services in 1985 and to Department of Emergency Management in 2000.
Today, the Virginia Department of Emergency Management works closely with local government, state and federal agencies (such as the Federal Emergency Management Agency) and voluntary organizations to provide resources and expertise in the event of a disaster. They offer disaster guidance in four areas: preparedness, response, recovery and mitigation.
Responsibility for the 911 Services Board and the Virginia Geographic Information Network Advisory Board were transferred from the Virginia Information Technologies Agency to the Virginia Dept. of Emergency Management in 2020 (HB 1003, Chap. 423, approved March 23, 2020.
Scope and Content
Disaster files, 1969-2012, consist of 23 boxes and are arranged in original order. These records document the planning, administrative activities, functions, major achievements and initiatives, and the implementation of agency programs, and are evidence of actions and policy decisions.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the original order.
Contents List
- Disaster files, 1969-2012.
  - Hurricane Fran, 1996 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Edouard, 1996 Aug/Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Bertha, 1996 July. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Opal, 1995 Oct. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Luis, 1995 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Felix, 1995 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Gordon, 1994 Nov. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Emily, 1993 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Andrew, 1992 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Lili, 1990 Oct. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Hugo, 1989 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Bob, 1991 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Charles, 1986 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Gloria, 1985 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane David, 1979 Sept. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Camille, 1969 July. (Box 1)
  - Hurricane Dennis and Floyd, 1999 Sept/Oct. (Box 2)
  - Hurricane Charley / Tropical Storm Bonnie, 2004 Aug. (Box 2)
  - Hurricane Katrina, 2005 Sept. (Box 2)
  - Hurricane Ophelia, 2005 Sept. (Box 2)
  - Ice storm, 1994 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Snow removal policy, undated. (Box 2)
  - Winter storm, 1996 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Storm - Russell County, 1996 July. (Box 2)
  - Storm damage - Eastern Shore (Northumberland and Accomack), 1996 Aug. (Box 2)
  - Storm damage - Danville / Pittsylvania County, 1996 Sept. (Box 2)
  - Heavy snow / coastal flooding, 1998 Jan. (Box 2)
  - Winter storm (2nd), 1998 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Severe storm - Buchanan County, 1998 June. (Box 2)
  - Ice storm, 1998 Dec 24. (Box 2)
  - Winter storm, 2000 Jan. (Box 2)
  - Winter storm, 2003 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Storm - Staunton, 2003 Aug. (Box 2)
  - Southwest Flood, 1984 May. (Box 3)
  - Patrick County Flood, 1985 Aug. (Box 3)
  - Flood, 1985 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Flooding, 1987 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - Buchanan and Dickenson Counties, 1987 July. (Box 3)
  - Flood, 1987 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - Town of Amherst, 1987 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - City of Covington, 1987. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - Village of Vensuviusby / South River, undated. (Box 3)
  - Dante Flooding - Bland and Russell Counties, 1996. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 2002 Mar 17-20. (Box 3)
  - Flooding - Soutwest Virginia, 2002 Apr 28-May 3. (Box 4)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 2003. (Box 4)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 2004 May. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Petersburg, 1993 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Pittsylvania County, 1996 June. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Centerville, 1996 June. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Pittsylvania County, 1998 Mar 20. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Fauquier County, 1990 Oct. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Augusta County, 1990 May. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Amelia County, 2003 May 9. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Henry County, 1994 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Tornado - Northumberland County (Hurricane Bertha), 1995 July. (Box 4)
  - Severe Storms, Tornado, Flooding, 2004 May 24. (Box 4)
  - Agricultural losses due to weather conditions, undated. (Box 4)
  - Drought, 1997. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services (VDACS) - Drought declarations, 2001-2002. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services (VDACS) - Drought declarations, 2003. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Consumer Services (VDACS) - Drought declarations, 2005-2012. (Box 4)
  - Crop damage due to drought, 1990 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Crop damage due to excessive rainfall, 1990 Fall. (Box 4)
  - Big Stone Gap water shortage, 2005 Oct. (Box 5)
  - Buchanan Co. mine fire, 2005 Mar. (Box 5)
  - Caroline Co. sanitary landfill, 1996 Aug. (Box 5)
  - Coleman Bridge closing, 1996. (Box 5)
  - Aircraft missing - Winchester area, 1990 June 4. (Box 5)
  - Aircraft crash - Tazewell Co., 1990 Aug 28. (Box 5)
  - Aircraft missing (private aircraft) - Manassas area, 1990 May 10. (Box 5)
  - Aircraft crash - Northumberland Co. (Town of Burgess), 1990 Aug 15. (Box 5)
  - Aircraft missing - Disputanta-Prince George Co., 1990 July 12. (Box 5)
  - Amtrak train accident - Newport News, 1992 Aug. (Box 5)
  - Avian Flu (Rockingham, Shenandoah, Page and Augusta), undated. (Box 5)
  - Avtex Plant incident, 1989 Nov. (Box 5)
  - Barrels on Cunningham's Island, 1990 May. (Box 5)
  - Benjamin Harrison Bridge, undated. (Box 5)
  - Big Stone Gap water tank collapse, 1985 July 19. (Box 5)
  - Bombing - Oklahoma City Federal Building, 1995 Apr. (Box 5)
  - Buena Vista Flood Control Project, 1994. (Box 5)
  - Chernobyl incident, undated. (Box 5)
  - Coal Strike, 1978. (Box 5)
  - Columbus - America Oil Spill - Tidewater, 1980 July 1. (Box 5)
  - Colonial Pipeline oil spill, 1980. (Box 5)
  - Crop damage due to frost and freezing, 1990 Spring. (Box 5)
  - Mudslides - Clifton Forge, 1987 Apr-May. (Box 5)
  - Winchester / Frederick Co. tire fire, undated. (Box 5)
  - World Trade Center / Pentagon Attack, 2001 Sept 11. (Box 5)
  - Winter Storm - Resource shortage, 1994 Jan. (Box 6)
  - Cold snap, 1994 Jan. (Box 6)
  - Ice storm, 1994 Feb-Mar. (Box 6)
  - Middle River, 1995. (Box 6)
  - Recovery Task Force, 1995 June. (Box 6)
  - Flooding, 1995 June. (Box 6)
  - Governor's brief, 1995 Aug 31. (Box 6)
  - Appalachian methane incident, 1995. (Box 6)
  - Fire suppression (Ice storm), 1994-1995. (Box 6)
  - Forestry (Ice storm), 1994-1995. (Box 6)
  - Drought, 1995. (Box 6)
  - Blizzard, 1996. (Box 6)
  - Hurricane Isabel binder, 2003. (Box 7)
  - Terrorism Brief for the Governor, 2002 Jan. (Box 7)
  - Terrorism, undated. (Box 7)
  - Terrorism Program, undated. (Box 7)
  - Hurricane Isabel appeal, 2003. (Box 7)
  - Flooding / Severe weather - Southwest Virginia, 2002. (Box 7)
  - Virginia Drought Monitoring Task Force, 2002. (Box 7)
  - State Recovery Task Force, undated. (Box 7)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Assessment Team Reports, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Community Relations, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Constituent mail, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Daily intelligence, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Damage estimates, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Impact on local government, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - ERT Fact Sheet, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - General information, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Incident action plan, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Individual assistance, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Information and planning, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Joint Information Center Disaster News, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Legislative issues, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Media monitoring, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Mitigation, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - National Situation Reports, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - FEMA press releases, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - State press releases, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Public assistance, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Hurricane Isabel - FEMA Situation Reports, 2003. (Box 8)
  - Mudslide - Buchanan Co. / Grundy, 1991 July. (Box 9)
  - Flooding Problems - Timberland / Shenandoah Co., 1991 July. (Box 9)
  - Drought - General information, 1999 Summer. (Box 9)
  - Drought, 1999 Summer. (Box 9)
  - Severe Storms - Excessive moisture and rain, 2003. (Box 9)
  - Water shortage - Buchanan / Tazewell Cos., 2003 Jan. (Box 9)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 1977 Apr. (Box 9)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia (Lee, Washington, and Wise Cos., and City of Bristol), 1977 Oct. (Box 9)
  - Flood - 408 Appeals, 1977 Nov. (Box 9)
  - Flash flooding - Southwest Virginia, 1978 Jan. (Box 9)
  - Southwest Virginia, 1977 Nov. (Box 9)
  - 408 Appeals, 1977 Apr. (Box 9)
  - Flooding - Buchanan Co., 1987 June 2. (Box 9)
  - Flood Assistance Request - Roanoke Co., 1984 Aug. (Box 9)
  - Flood - Accomack Co., 1984 Mar 29. (Box 9)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 1984 May 6-7. (Box 9)
  - Pike County, Kentucky - Bridge, 1984. (Box 9)
  - Federal / State Disaster Assistance Agreement, 1984. (Box 9)
  - Flood Assistance Request - Alleghany Co., 1984 Aug. (Box 9)
  - Tire fire - Winchester, 1985 Sept. (Box 10)
  - Tire fire - King and Queen Co., 1986 Jan 23. (Box 10)
  - Fires - Southwestern Virginia, 1987 Nov. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Madison Co., 1987. (Box 10)
  - Fiberglass Engineering Co. - Fauquier Co., 1988 Mar 23. (Box 10)
  - Forest fire - York Co., 1988 June 27. (Box 10)
  - Forest fire - Rockbridge Co., 1988 July 4. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Fauquier and Page Cos., 1988 July 11. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Town of Ivanhoe, 1989 Apr 20. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Shredded Products Corp., Montvale, 1989 Oct. (Box 10)
  - Tire fire - Sussex Co., 1991 Mar 20. (Box 10)
  - Forest fires, 1994 Nov. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Martinsville (SBA), 1995 Apr. (Box 10)
  - Forest fires due to drought, 1995 Apr. (Box 10)
  - Forest fires - Assistance to Kentucky, 1995 Apr. (Box 10)
  - City of Danville, 1997 Nov. (Box 10)
  - Forest fires / Drought - Executive orders, 1998 Dec. (Box 10)
  - Florida's fires - Provided assistance through EMAC, 1998 June. (Box 10)
  - Fire - Purgatory Mountain, 1999 Aug. (Box 10)
  - Montana fires (EMAC), 2000. (Box 10)
  - Tire fire - Roanoke, 2002- Mar. (Box 10)
  - Commonwealth of Virgina Emergency Fuel Storage Facility (CVEFSF), 1990-. (Box 11)
  - Alternative Remediation Projects, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Army Corps of Engineers, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Budget / Capital Outlay Monthly Reports, 1991-1992. (Box 11)
  - Budget / Capital Outlay Monthly Reports, 1992-1994. (Box 11)
  - Enironmental Protection Agency (EPA) - Agreement, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Enironmental Protection Agency (EPA) - Consent order, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Enironmental Protection Agency (EPA) - General information, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Enironmental Protection Agency (EPA) - Quartery Status Reports, 1990. (Box 11)
  - Engineering Science, 1990. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1996. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1994. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1993. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1992. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1991. (Box 11)
  - General information, 1990. (Box 12)
  - News articles, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Penalties, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Plan for Restoration of the CVEFSF, 1990 Nov 6. (Box 12)
  - Presentation to Senate Finance Committee, 1990 Nov 16. (Box 12)
  - Report to Governor Wilder, 1991. (Box 12)
  - State Water Control Board - General information, 1990. (Box 12)
  - State Water Control Board - Discharge Monitoring Reports, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Tank Cleaning Contract, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Updates to the Secretary of Public Safety, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Waste Management and DES - Agreement, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Waste Management - General information, 1990. (Box 12)
  - Workplan, 1991 Feb 7. (Box 12)
  - Reports, 1996. (Box 12)
  - Severe storm and flooding - Northeaster, 2009 Nov. (Box 13)
  - Winter storm / Snowstorm, 2009 Dec. (Box 13)
  - Severe Winter storm / Snowstorm, 2010. (Box 13)
  - Hurricane Sandy, 2012. (Box 13)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Agreements, regulations, executive orders, requests and approvals, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Community Relations Daily Reports, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Constituent mail, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Daily Status Reports, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Disaster News, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Damage assessment, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - EMAC, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Hazard mitigation, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - IFG Appeal letters, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Indirect costs, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - General information, letters and memos, 1999. (Box 14)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Media monitoring, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Mitigation strategy, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Mosquitos, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - News releases, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Preliminary damage assessments, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Response and recovery, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Situation Reports (State DFO), 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Situation Reports (FEMA), 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Situation Reports (EOC), 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Situation Reports (Local), 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Southampton Agriculture Business Park, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - VDOT, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Floyd - Staffing, 1999. (Box 15)
  - Hurricane Gordon, 2000 Sept. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Irene, 1999 Oct. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Gert, 1999 Sept. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Dennis, 1999 Aug. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Georges - Assistance to Missippi (EMAC), 1998 Sept. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Georges - Assistance to Florida (EMAC), 1998 Sept. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Bonnie, 1998 Aug. (Box 16)
  - Hurricane Fran, 1996 Sept. (Box 16)
  - Flood - Chronological, 1995 June. (Box 17)
  - Blizzard and Flood Master File, 1996. (Box 18)
  - Blizzard and Flood Master File - Chronological, 1996. (Box 18)
  - Blizzard and Flood Master File - Finance and time data, 1996. (Box 18)
  - Blizzard and Flood Master File - Blizzard and Flood Situation Reports, 1996. (Box 18)
  - Flooding - Accomack Co., 1989 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Buchanan Co., 1989 Oct. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Fairfax Co., 1989 June. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Fauquier, 1989 July 20. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Floyd County, 1989 Sept. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Fredericksburg, 1989 Dec. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Giles Co., 1989 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Henry Co. (Jordan Creek), 1989 July. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - James City Co., 1989 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding and storm damage - Loudoun Co., 1989 June. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Manassas Park, 1989 July. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Northampton Co., 1989 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Patrick Co., 1989 June. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Russell Co., 1989 Oct 16-17. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Stafford Co., 1989 Dec. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Tazewell Co., 1989 Oct 16-17. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Warren Co., 1989 July 19-20. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - York Co., 1989 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Lee, Wise, Buchanan and Dickenson Cos., 1989 July 15. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Atkins Flood problem in Smyth Co., 1989-1990. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - City of Portsmouth, 1990. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Tidewater area, 1990 Aug. (Box 19)
  - Flooding (potential) - Town of Timberville, 1991. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Salem (Mason Creek), 1991. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Emergency Declaration / General information, 1992 Apr 21-22. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 1992 June 3-5. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Dickenson Co., 1992 May 19. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Winter storm, 1993 Mar. (Box 19)
  - Flooding, 1993 Ap. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Midwest U.S., 1993 July. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Town of Monterey, 1994. (Box 19)
  - Flooding - Tidewater and Roanoke, 1978 Apr 25-27. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Buchanan Co. disaster, undated. (Box 20)
  - Flooding (flash) - Rappahannock Co., 1979 Aug 28-29. (Box 20)
  - Flooding / Disaster - Patrick Co., 1979 Sept 21-22. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Wise Co., 1982 Sept 14. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Buchanan Co., 1982 May. (Box 20)
  - Flooding / Disaster - Georgia, 1994 July. (Box 20)
  - Flooding, 1995 July. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia, 1995 June. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia / FEMA, 1995 June. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Town of Orange / De-obligation of Funds, 1995 June. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Counties reqesting assistance / General information, 1995 June. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Russell Co., 1996 May. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Bland Co., 1996 May. (Box 20)
  - Flooding Disaster, 1996 Jan. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - eAtkins Flooding Project, 2000 Feb. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Roanoke City 2000 July. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Buchanan Co., 2000 July. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Southwest Virginia (Dickenson, Scott, Smyth, Wise), 2001 July 29. (Box 20)
  - Flooding - Tazewell Co., 2001 July 8. (Box 20)
  - Freeze - Chesapeake Bay, 1977. (Box 21)
  - Water Resource Emergency - Southwest Virginia, 1989 Oct. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1983 Summer. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1984. (Box 21)
  - Water Issue - Lee Co., 1984 Apr. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1985. (Box 21)
  - Freeze, 1986 Winter. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1986. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1987. (Box 21)
  - Mudslide - Clifton Forge, 1987 Apr-May. (Box 21)
  - Water issue - Dickenson Co., 1987. (Box 21)
  - Landslide - Town of Appalachia, 1988. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1988. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1991. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1993. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1994. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1995. (Box 21)
  - Drought - Boones Mill water crisis, 1985. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1997. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 1998. (Box 21)
  - Drought - Forest Fire emergency, 1998 Dec. (Box 21)
  - Drought, 2001. (Box 21)
  - Flooding - Huntington - Constituent mail, 2006. (Box 22)
  - Hurricane Isabel - Correspondence, 2003-2004. (Box 22)
  - Tropical Storm Ernesto - Declaration, general info, 2004 Aug. (Box 22)
  - FEMA - State agreements, report, letters, memos - Chronicle files, 2004. (Box 22)
  - Disaster - Tazewell Co. (binder), 2001 July. (Box 23)
  - Disaster - Tazewell Co. - Situation Reports (binder), 2001 July. (Box 23)
  - Severe Weather - Southwest Virginia (binder), 2003 Nov 18-19. (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous disasters, undated. (Box 23)